Bruce Zu's Resume

- Like algorithm, math, coding to defeat every kind technology issue and challenge. I appreciate
 hacker culture, concise and quick code which is improving the life of people. Excited to work
 in open source community and interested in distributed application systems. Having passion of
 continuous improvement through refactoring and introducing new technologies.
- 14-year Java/Java EE experience since 2002. Full stack or server side development.
- Contributed to **open source** Google Gerrit Code Review since 2011.
- Administrator experience (8 years) of web applications running on Linux.

[small Gray]# 1015 Nottingham PL, San Jose, CA 95117 | (626) 747-6721 | English, Mandarin | zu.bruce@yahoo.com Linkedin Facebook Github#

Apr 2015 - Apr 2016
Relocated to CA from Beijing
Following Gerrit community | Acquiring Data Structures and Algorithms
Got **EAD** and **SSN** in April, 2016 | Looking for a job now in CA or Seattle | *I can work immediately*

EMPLOYMENT

Sony Mobile — Senior Software Engineer, full stack, mainly focus on back end

Sep 2011 - Apr 2015

Sony Mobile Gerrit team is a global team (4 \sim 8 members from Sweden, Tokyo, Brazil and Beijing) supporting 7000+ inner end users.

- Tackled daily **Gerrit/Git/Repo** related issues and feature requirements for CM users, Git Admin and developers.
- Contributed 140+ commits to improve and strengthen Gerrit functions to make users convenient.
- Received 2 awards for outstanding contributions for software development.

Nov 2010 - Sep 2011

Sony Mobile Jenkins team is a global team (4 ~ 8 members) including Beijing, Lund and Tokyo sites.

- Tackled daily **Jenkins** related issues for developers and CM users.
- Developed Gerrit-trigger-plugin.
- Maintained Jenkins servers.

Canon — DBA & Senior Software Engineer, back end

Apr 2007 - Mar 2010

E-Order, E-Bank, E-Parts ... web applications

- Perform **query optimization**, tuning of complex queries, write efficient SQL and Stored Procedures.
- Tackled backup & restore issues of **DB2** databases, **MS SQL server** databases.
- **Developed** and maintained a **real-time** application to exchange data between web applications and core application.

CS&S — Software Engineer, full stack, mainly focus on back end

Mar 2003 - Feb 2007

Large scale distributed web applications built for Guangdong Province China using **Java EE**, **Oracle**, **BEA Weblogic**.

- Designed and developed payment module of Centralized Taxes Payment Application.
- Designed Social Insurance Payment Application.
- Received **several awards** for outstanding performance in team.

Cernet — Intern, full stack, mainly focus on back end

Mar 2002 - Dec 2002

E-payment Application

• Developed all features of admin module from front-end to back-end using **Java EE**, **Oracle**, **IBoss**.

EDUCATION

Sep 2000 - Mar 2003

University of Science and Technology Beijing - Master

Sep 1994 - Mar 1998

University of Science and Technology Hebei - Bachelor

SKILLS (years)

Open Source Software Development Gerrit/Git (5), Jenkins (5), BUCK (3), Maven (2)

Java/Java EE (14), Python (2)

C/C++ (2), Javascript/HTML/CSS (2)

Linux (7), Bash

Google Guice (5), Google Guaua (5), Google GWT (5)

RESTful API, develop client & server side

Tomcat (3), Jetty, Bea Weblogic (3), IBM WebShpere (2) SQL DB: Oracle (5), Postgres (4), IBM DB2 (3), SQL Server (3) IBM MQ (2), Apache Lucene Scrum/Agile/Sprint (3)

Ability

- An independent quick learner especially on Java technologies.
 When I worked in SonyMobile, I was assigned to develop Gerrit and Jenkins plugin which I had never heard of at the very beginning. However, I could shift output quickly without any help since I am good at Java.
- Positive team spirit and interpersonal skills.
- Excellent attention to detail, troubleshooting and analytical skills.

NOTE

If you want more information, please refer the following Deployment Detail information

EMPLOYMENT DETAIL

Sony Mobile

Sep 2011 - Apr 2015

Job Title

Senior Software Engineer, full stack, mainly focus on back end.

Job Function

I was a member of global Gerrit development team, supporting Git Admin team, CM team and developers by delivering new features and bugfixes. Members are from Sweden, Tokyo, Brazil and Beijing. We also keep close relation with other Gerrit community core contributors who works for Google, SAP, Qualcomm and OpenStack.

Application introduction

Gerrit Code Review

Gerrit provides access via browser, **RESTful API** and **SSH Command line**. Gerrit select **GWT** as its web framework, uses **CodeMirror** to show the **git diff** result on web. A new UI is under building using **Polymer**. Gerrit replaced nearly all **GWT RPC** implementation with its own **RESTful API**. The **SSH Command line** features are built with **Apache MINA**'s sub project **Apache SSHD**. Gerrit notification functions including **Hook**, **Stream-event** and **E-mail**. Gerrit stores data in **Git** repositories and **SQL database**. Gerrit does not use **Hibernate**. Instead, it supports 9 kinds of **SQL database** with its own **open source** tiny **ORM** library, which is built by using **ObjectWeb ASM 3**, **H2** and **ANTLR 3**, e.g. **Oracle**, **MySQL**, **H2**, **PostgreSQL**, **DB2**.

However, Gerrit is moving the data stored in DB into git notes. This is a step towards implementing open-source version of multi-master feature. Gerrit caches search results in memory, disk of server side and client side via browser. Gerrit builds second index using Lucene and Protocol Buffers. Gerrit provides search function, and the grammar is built by using Antlr 3. Gerrit has replication function, which now is a plugin, to enable master-slave mode. Gerrit uses Google Guice, not Spring, as dependency injection framework. Gerrit supports developing Gerrit plugin. Gerrit uses BUCK to build source code, run Junit test, wrap release file (war). BUCK runs faster that Maven. Gerrit provides init command to do every initial works and startup Gerrit automatically. Gerrit has tons framework.

The Sony Mobile Gerrit server

Gerrit server runs in **Tomcat** web container behind an **Apache** web server. Gerrit server is **master-slave** mode, one master server and on average 7 **slave servers** * 3 **sites** accessed by 7000+ end users in total. Sony Mobile Gerrit server uses **PostgreSQL** that has replication features. Each Gerrit slave server has a **PostgreSQL** database. On each site, the Gerrit slave servers are located behind balance servers that balance the requests from local developers and local **Jenkins** servers.

Achievements

Develop

Some features, e.g.:

- ☑ Create project (SSH command and RESTful API)
- ☑ Add file comment to a patch
- **☑** Enable branch specified label
- ☑ Add reviewers in batch by **LDAP** group
- ✓ Add new system configuration options
- ☑ Enable register email registered automatically

Details: my commits contributed to Gerrit community.

Daily support

- ☑ Tackled issues related to Gerrit, Apache, Tomcat with CM user and Git Admin
- ☑ Tried new Gerrit version and Gerrit plugins in Test Environment

No 2010 ~ Sep 2011

Job Function

Jenkins master.

Job Title

Staff Engineer

Application introduction

Sony mobile has few **Jenkins servers** in each site with hundreds of slave machines for developers, CM teams.

Achievements

Admin Jenkins Server

- ☑ Evaluated/Upgraded Jenkins new version and Jenkins plugins
- Setup and configured new Jenkins slaves. Allocated slave groups to Jenkins jobs, Tuned slave groups
- ☑ Monitored Jenkins server/jobs/slaves and tackled issues

Develop

▼ Took part in developing Jenkins plugin: Gerrit-trigger-plugin

Canon China

Apr 2007 - Mar 2010

Job Title

Senior Software Engineer, back end.

Job Function

Supervise all local web applications

Application introduction

Cannon China local applications

Web applications, e.g. e-order, e-bank, e-parts ... They are built using Java/Java EE, DB2 or MS SQL Server. Their databases need exchange data with core application that is built using AS400 and DB2.

Achievements

DBA

- ☑ Perform query optimization and tuning of complex queries, write efficient SQL and Stored Procedures. That access several million rows across several database tables. Tuned SQL statement of web applications, e.g. reduced the running time of some SQL statements to be less than 5 seconds from 2+ minutes.
- ☑ Setup MS SQL Server database backup plan and carried it out.
- ☑ Tacked day-to-day issues of DB2 backup to tape and wrote tutorial.

Develop using the API of IBM MQ and Java RMI:

☑ Designed, developed, tested, deployed and maintained a real-time application used to sync data between web applications and core applications.

China Software & Service

Mar 2003 - Feb 2007

Job Title

Software Engineer, full stack, mainly focus on back end

Job Function

With other members developed 2 web applications for Guangdong Province China.

- Centralized Taxes Payment Application.
- Social Insurance Payment Application.

Application introduction

Centralized Taxes Payment Application

The application provides local tax services for the whole province. It is a large-scale distributed Java EE based web application built with Oracle RAC and Weblogic cluster. The number of GDP and people of Guandong Province is greater than that of Taiwan. The number of this application's online users (2000+) and concurrent users is very tremendous. It is also a big data application. It is multi-tier, browser/server mode and client/server mode architecture. Users can access it via telephone, browser and client side application. It also communicates with other applications of banks and other government departments.

Achievements

Design and coding features like online payment and printing cash receipt, General-purpose Tax Payment Certificate.

Application introduction

Social Insurance Payment Application

This application is used to collect 5 kinds of social insurance fee from employer for their employee. It force the employer to pay these social insurance together with the local taxes

I was in charge of system requirement and system design.

Achievements

Design:

- ☑ Wrote out system requirement with end user. Made clear the boundary of system, wrote out user cases.
- ☑ Combed out the business data flow, draw out business data module.
- ☑ Created physical data module, DB scheme.
- Divided system into sub modules.

ETL:

☑ Took part in ETL work between old application DB and new application DB.

Cernet — Intern

Mar 2002 - Dec 2002

Job Title

Software Engineer, full stack, mainly focus on back end.

Job Function

Took part in developing E_Payment web application

Application introduction

E_Payment application

It is online payment application like Paypal to provide payment service used by Cernet web site. Its framework mocked the Sun pet store using **JavaScript**, **JSP**, **Servlet**, **JDBC**, **EJB**

Achievements

Developed admin module of E-payment application from the **front-end** to **back-end** Features includes

- **☑** Register/update new user information.
- ☑ Manage user authority via user's group.

Developed common library

☑ Defined **DTD**, a Document Type Definition, and developed a parser to parse a given **XML** according the DTD.